mapcruzin.com 2019-04-01

# Cookies, Privacy, Disclaimer and fair use notice

January 30, 2020 

**Didn't find what you are looking for?** **Email me** **and I'll find it for you.**

**Progressive Links**

**MapCruzin Consulting**  
Data Research and GIS Specialists. 

GIS Tutorials

GIS Basics

GIS Terminology

| 

On This Page: Your Privacy \- Fair Use \- Disclaimer

Sponsors

##  **Privacy Policy for mapcruzin.com**

This is our privacy policy. If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#2d404446486d404c5d4e5f58574443034e4240125e584f47484e5910604c5d6e5f585744430d7d5f445b4c4e540d7c58485e59444243). 

At mapcruzin.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information that is received and collected by mapcruzin.com and how it is used. 

**Log Files**  
Like many other Web sites, mapcruzin.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. 

**Cookies and Web Beacons**  
mapcruzin.com does not use cookies. 

DoubleClick DART Cookie 

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on mapcruzin.com. 
  * Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to mapcruzin.com and other sites on the Internet. 
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - [http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include ....  
Google Adsense  
Commission Junction  
Clickbank  
Amazon 

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on mapcruzin.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see. 

mapcruzin.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. 

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. mapcruzin.com's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. 

Special Note About Google Advertising 

Any advertisements served by Google, Inc., and affiliated companies may be controlled using cookies. These cookies allow Google to display ads based on your visits to this site and other sites that use Google advertising services. Learn how to opt out of Google's cookie usage. As mentioned above, any tracking done by Google through cookies and other mechanisms is subject to Google's own privacy policies. 

About Google advertising: What is the DoubleClick DART cookie? The DoubleClick DART cookie is used by Google in the ads served on publisher websites displaying AdSense for content ads. When users visit an AdSense publisher’s website and either view or click on an ad, a cookie may be dropped on that end user’s browser. The data gathered from these cookies will be used to help AdSense publishers better serve and manage the ads on their site(s) and across the web. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy. Go here for more information: [http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/](https://www.google.com/privacy/ads/). 

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites. 

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#abc6c2c0ceebc6cadbc8d9ded1c2c585c8c4c694d8dec9c1cec8df96e6cadbe8d9ded1c2c58bfbd9c2ddcac8d28bfadeced8dfc2c4c5). 

You can find additional information about your privacy online in [Appendix A of the NAI Self-Regulatory principles for publishers](https://www.networkadvertising.org/pdfs/NAI_principles.pdf) (PDF). Please note that the NAI may change this sample language at any time. 

Sponsors

##  **Fair Use**

The idea of a free press in America is one that we hold in the highest regard. This site contains copyrighted material the use of which has not always been specifically authorized by the copyright owner. We are making such material available in our efforts to advance understanding of environmental, political, human rights, economic, scientific, and social justice issues, sustainable development, environmental, community and worker health, democracy, public disclosure, corporate accountability, and social justice issues, etc. 

In many cases we have included the full text of the article rather than a simple link because we have found that links frequently go "bad" or change over time. We believe this constitutes a "fair use" of any such copyrighted material as provided for in section 107 of the US Copyright Law. In accordance with Title 17 U.S.C. Section 107, the material on this site is distributed without fee or payment of any kind to those who have expressed a prior interest in receiving the included information for research and educational purposes. If you wish to use copyrighted material from this site for purposes of your own that go beyond 'fair use', you must obtain permission from the copyright owner. 

## **Disclaimer**

Among the thousands of pages posted here for your consideration, there will doubtless be some that you find useless, and possibly offensive, but we believe you will be perceptive enough to realize that even the things you disagree with have some value in terms of promoting your own further self-definition and insight. Our site is a smorgasbord of material...take what you wish and click or scroll right past that which doesn't interest you. 

We suggest you don't make 'assumptions' about our official position on issues that are discussed here. That is not what this site is about. We believe it to be unwise to sweep controversy under the carpet. We also firmly believe people should not only read material which they agree with. 

The GIS software tools, programs and resources you find on this site come from a variety of U.S. government and private sources. While we try to assure the accuracy of this material, we cannot promise that it is absolutely accurate. We do promise that using what you find here will be fun, entertaining or educational - perhaps even frustrating. Beyond this, we make no guarantee as to its suitability for any purpose. We assume no liability or responsibility for errors or inaccuracies. Please understand that you use these tools, programs and resources at your own risk. 

On This Page: Your Privacy \- Fair Use \- Disclaimer

Thanks, 

Didn't find what you are looking for? We've been online since 1996 and have created 1000's of pages. Search below and you may find just what you are looking for. 

* * *

Michael R. Meuser  
Data Research & GIS Specialist 

MapCruzin.com is an independent firm specializing in GIS project development and data research. We created the first U.S. based interactive toxic chemical facility maps on the internet in 1996 and we have been online ever since. Learn more about us and our services. 

Have a project in mind? If you have data, GIS project or custom shapefile needs **contact Mike**. 

Contact Us

Report Broken Links

|
